birkenstock.com 2019-07-27

# Privacy Policy

Birkenstock USA, LP (“Birkenstock”, “we”, or “us”) respects your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes the personal data collected or processed when you use our website (the “Site”). It also explains how your personal data is collected, use, share and protected, what options you have relating to your personal data, and how you can contact us.. If we change this Notice, we will post an updated version on the Site and change the date at the bottom of this page to reflect the most recent revision.

This Privacy Notice is incorporated by reference into, and is subject to, the Terms of Use. By using this Site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Notice and the Terms of Use.

  * Information Collection
  * Information Use
  * Data Analytics
  * Information Sharing
  * Security
  * Links to Other Websites
  * Remarketing
  * Newsletter
  * Your Choices
  * Children’s Privacy
  * Information for Users Outside the United States
  * Contact Us

## Information Collection

We may collect information directly from you, including personal information such as your name, email address, shipping/billing address, phone number, credit card number, and other personally identifiable information, when you visit our Site, place an order online or by phone, save your information with us online, contact us with a question or concern, or participate in a contest, promotion, or survey. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of certain features. We maintain a record of your product interests and the purchases you make online or by phone. We may combine all of this information with information about you that we acquire from our joint marketing partners, and from unrelated third parties.

We also may collect information automatically when you visit the Site. Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login; computer and connection information such as browser type, version, and time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system, and platform; purchase history; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from the Site, including date and time; cookie number; and products you searched for or viewed. We may also use browser data on certain parts of our Site, for fraud prevention and other purposes. During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

Please note that any comments, feedback, suggestions, ideas, and other submissions that you disclose, submit or offer to us in connection with your use of this Site (collectively "Comments"), are subject to our Terms of Use, which explain how we may use and disclose such Comments and/or information about your demographics and use of the Site.  

## Information Use

We may use your information about you to operate the Site and to deliver the content and services you request. In addition, we may use information about you for other lawful purposes, including to:

  * Process and fulfill your order, including to send you emails to confirm your order status and shipment;
  * Respond to requests, Comments, or questions, and to provide customer support;
  * Communicate with you, such as by sending you information about our products, services, and promotions;
  * If you are an existing customer of Birkenstock (for example, if you have placed an order with us), we may use the contact details you provided to send you marketing communications about similar Birkenstock products or services, where permitted by applicable law (unless you have opted-out). In other cases, we ask for your consent to send you marketing information. Learn more about your shopping preferences, to help personalize and improve your online experience;
  * Improve the Site and other products and services we may offer;
  * Monitor and analyze Site usage, trends, and statistics;
  * Protect the security and integrity of the Site, prevent fraudulent transactions, illegal use, violations of our Terms of Use, or other misuse, and monitor against threats;
  * Comply with legal requirements, industry standards, and our policies; or

For any other purpose, we may also use your personal data in other ways and will provide specific notice at the time of collection and obtain your consent where necessary.

## Data Analytics

Our Site uses “cookies”, which are small data files that are stored on your computer when you visit a website. Cookies enable you to shop on our Site and may be used in a variety of ways to enhance or personalize your online browsing and shopping experience. For example, we may use cookies to remember the items in your shopping cart, store your preferences, and recognize you when you return to our Site, track your orders, and monitor and maintain information about your use of our Site.

You may be able to set your browser to not accept cookies, or to notify you when you are sent a cookie so that you may decide whether or not to accept it. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to access your account information or make purchases on the Site.

This Site uses third-party web analytics services such as Google Analytics to help us analyze how visitors use the Site. To learn more about opting out of data collection through Google Analytics, [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Your web browser may have settings that allow you to transmit a “Do Not Track” signal when you visit various websites or use online services. Like many websites, this Site is not designed to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from browsers. To learn more about “Do Not Track” signals, [click here](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

Information about your use of the Site and other websites may be collected across time and services, and used for various purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and to deliver relevant and retargeted content, including interest-based advertising.  

## Information Sharing

We do not sell, rent, or share your information, except as is described in this Notice. We may permit our agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers to access information collected through the Site to carry out work on our behalf. For example, we may share your information with our service providers who help us to fulfill customer orders, send communications, or conduct surveys. We do not authorize these service providers to make any other use or disclosure of your information.

In the event of a sale, merger, or other transfer of our assets, personal information and other information we have collected as described in this Notice may be among the transferred business assets, or may be shared with third parties as part of the transaction or negotiation.

We may release your information if required to do so by law, or if we believe that such action is necessary to comply with any law, or to respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant. We also reserve the right to disclose personally identifiable information as appropriate or necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, to protect the security or integrity of the Site, or to protect anyone’s rights, property, or personal safety.  

## Security

Although the security of information transmitted via the Internet cannot be guaranteed, we strive to provide you with a safe and convenient shopping experience. We have implemented appropriate safeguards to protect the security and privacy of personal information we obtain through the Site. For example, when you enter your personal information on our Site, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect your information as it is transmitted to us. To make sure you are accessing our secure server before you submit personal financial information, look at the lower left-hand corner of your browser. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending upon your browser), then SSL is active. To double-check for security, look at the URL or Location line of your browser. If you have accessed a secure server, the first characters of the address in that line should change from "http" to "https."  

## Links to Other Websites

For your convenience and information, this Site may contain links to other websites that may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the content, privacy practices, advertising, or products of any linked site that we do not control. We recommend that you review the privacy policy of any site that you access through this Site.  

**Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources, including the following:

  * Identity and Contact Data from publicly available sources;
  * Contact, Payment and Transaction Data from payment processor and fraud detection and prevention companies;
  * Identity and/or Contact Data from friends or people you know and who have asked us to contact you;
  * Technical Data from analytics providers like Google;
  * Technical Data from search information providers;
  * Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, User Content, and/or Friends Data from social media channels like Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest, and Twitter.
  * Identity, Contact, Profile, and/or Usage Data from advertising networks and marketing lists; and
  * Identity, Contact, and/or Profile Data from marketing insights companies like Experian.

## Remarketing

**Use of Google Remarketing:** This website uses the remarketing feature of Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). This feature makes it possible to present interest-based advertising to website visitors as part of the Google Network. The remarketing feature uses "cookies", small text files, which are stored on your computer. They are used to remember your information and settings when you visit websites that are part of Google's advertising network. These websites can then show you relevant ads that refer to the content you previously viewed on websites that use the remarketing feature of Google.

According to Google, it does not collect any personally identifiable information in this process. If you do not want the remarketing feature to be used, however, you can always disable it by changing the appropriate settings at <https://www.google.com/settings/ads>.

**Use of Facebook Remarketing:** On our website, the remarketing feature of Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”) is used. It allows us to show visitors to our website personalized, content-related Facebook ads when they visit the social network Facebook.

Our website therefore contains remarketing tags from Facebook. Through these tags, your browser establishes a direct connection to the Facebook servers when you visit our website. Facebook is informed which of our websites you have visited and can assign this information to your personal Facebook profile. This information then enables us to display personalized, interest-related Facebook ads.

Please refer to Facebook’s [Data Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation) for information on the purpose and scope of data collection and the processing and use of the data by Facebook, as well as the rights and settings to protect your privacy. If you do not want Facebook to assign the collected information directly to your Facebook profile, you can disable the function [here](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_=_) when you are logged in to Facebook.

**Use of Rocket Fuel Inc.’s Remarketing Feature:** We use the services of Rocket Fuel Inc., San Francisco, California, USA, ([www.rocketfuel.com](http://www.rocketfuel.com/)), to collect statistical data about the use of our website and to optimize the site for you accordingly. More information about how this data is processed and used can be found in Rocket Fuel Inc.’s privacy policy, which is available here: [www.rocketfuel.com/privacy/](http://www.rocketfuel.com/privacy/) You can prevent Rocket Fuel Inc. from collecting and saving this data about you in the future by visiting [www.rocketfuel.com/opt-out/](http://www.rocketfuel.com/opt-out/) and clicking on the word “here” in the section labeled “Opt Out”.

**Use of Kenshoo:** On our website, we use the services of Kenshoo, 22 4th Street, 7th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Kenshoo”). This feature makes it possible to present interest-based advertising to website visitors as part of the Google & Bing Networks. The feature uses "cookies", small text files, which are stored on your computer. They are used to remember your information and settings when you visit websites that are part of Google's and Bing’s advertising network. These websites can then show you relevant ads that refer to the content you previously viewed on our site pages.

Please refer to Kenshoo’s Data Policy for information on the purpose and scope of data collection and the processing and use of the data by Kenshoo, as well as the rights to protect your privacy. To learn more about Kenshoo’s Data Policy including their services, and your rights, please click here [kenshoo.com/privacy-policy/](https://kenshoo.com/privacy-policy/)

**Use of Nanigans:** On our website, we use the services of Nanigans Inc., 100 Summer St, Boston, MA, USA (“Nanigans”). It allows us to collect statistical data to provide more interest based, content related advertisements when visiting Facebook Inc. properties.

Our website therefore contains marketing tags from Nanigans. Through these tags, your browser establishes a direct connection to the Nanigans servers when you visit our website. Nanigans is informed which of our website pages you have visited. This information then enables us to display personalized, interest-related ads on Facebook Inc. properties.

Please refer to Nanigans’ Data Policy for information on the purpose and scope of data collection and the processing and use of the data by Nanigans, as well as the rights to protect your privacy. To learn more about Nanigans’ Data Policy including their services, and your rights, please click here [www.nanigans.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.nanigans.com/privacy-policy/)

**Use of Hotjar:** On our website, we use Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking here <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy>

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this opt-out link <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>

**Use of Convert:** On our website, we use the services of Convert Insights, Inc., 340 South Lemon Avenue, #9512 Walnut, California 91789, USA (“Convert”). Convert is a processor that makes it possible to improve the performance of online businesses and marketing activities through online website optimization services. The feature uses "cookies", small text files, which are stored on your individual device. They are used to analyze and compile statistics about the use of our website (e.g. how many users/visitors and what they viewed) in order to improve our website (analytics, performance and overall experience).

**Use of Connexity:** On our website, we use the services of Connexity, Inc., 2120 Colorado Ave, California 90404, USA (“Connexity”). Connexity is a processor that makes it possible for us to review the performance of our marketing activities with Connexity through services on our website. The feature uses "cookies", small text files, which are stored on your individual device. They are used to compile data and statistics about our marketing activities (e.g. how many users/visitors made purchases) in order to improve our website and services to you. Connexity uses this data purely for business purposes and does not share and/or sell them.

## Newsletter

If you subscribe to our newsletter, the information necessary or communicated by you will be used for this purpose in order to enable us to periodically send you the newsletter via e-mail. A third party, salesforce.com EMEA Limited, Floor 26 Salesforce Tower, 110 Bishopsgate, London, EC2N 4AY, United Kingdom, is responsible for the technical aspects of sending out the newsletter. The extent of disclosed (personal) information is, however, limited to the minimum necessary for sending out the newsletter.

After providing your content to receive our newsletter by subscribing, you will receive an e-mail confirming your opt-in.

If you no longer wish to receive the newsletter, you may unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time using a variety of available communication means (such as clicking the unsubscribe link in the newsletter or sending us an e-mail, or a letter by post) at no cost to you except for the standard rates associated with your chosen means of communication.  

## Your Choices

You may review and change certain personal information we collect, such as your name and contact information. To access your information, simply sign in to your account using your email address and password, and you will be able to edit your personal information. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a password) to verify your identity before granting your profile access to make corrections. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password and account information at all times.

You may opt out of receiving promotional email communications from us by following the instructions provided in those communications. Please note that even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications, we may continue to send you non-promotional emails, such as emails regarding your orders and other business transactions with us.

You may opt-out from having your personal information used for certain purposes. For example, if you purchase a product or service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you may opt-out by following the instructions included in each email communication or by emailing us at [privacy@birkenstockusa.com](mailto:privacy@birkenstockusa.com). Please indicate which forms of communication you would like to opt out of in your email. i.e. direct mail, email, etc.  
As discussed above, many web browsers include options that allow users to disable existing cookies or stop accepting new cookies. Please note that if you disable cookies certain features of this Site may not work properly, and disabling cookies may invalidate opt outs that rely on cookies to function.  

## Children’s Privacy

The site is not designed to attract children, and is not directed at, or intended for use by, children under the age of 13. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"), we do not request or collect any personally identifiable information (“PII”) from anyone who we know to be under the age of 13, nor do we knowingly sell or ship any items ordered through this Website directly to anyone under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you should not register with, order or purchase from, or provide information to or from, Steve Madden. If we become aware that a user of our Website is under the age of 13 and has provided an online registration or other PII without prior verifiable parental consent, we will take all commercially reasonable steps to delete such information from our files and not to use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or allowed by law).  

## Information for Users Outside the United States

If you are visiting this Site from outside the United States, please be aware that information we collect through the Site may be transferred to and stored on our servers in the United States. By using this Site, you acknowledge and consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States as described in this Privacy Notice. Please be aware that the data protection laws and regulations applicable to your personal data transferred to the United States may be different from the laws in your country of residence.  

## Contact Us

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Notice or about our information practices, you may contact us via email at [privacy@birkenstockusa.com](mailto:privacy@birkenstockusa.com), or by writing to:

Birkenstock USA, LP  
Legal Department  
8171 Redwood Blvd  
Novato, CA 94945

Last Updated: June 2019
